Guide to the Erich Maria Remarque Papers MSS.095
Fales Library and Special Collections
- Series 3B: Correspondence to Remarque, 1920-1970; 1.75 Linear Feet in 4 manuscript boxes.
  - Legal -- O. Uhlmann, 1934 (Box 87, Folder 40, Item 1)
  - Legal -- Joel E. Sammet, 1945 (Box 87, Folder 40, Item 2)
  - Legal -- Georg Gautschi, 1960 (Box 87, Folder 40, Item 3)
  - Legal -- W. Metzger-Cavalli, 1965 (Box 87, Folder 40, Item 4)
  - Legal -- Sergio Salvioni, 1965 (Box 87, Folder 40, Item 5)
  - Legal -- William H. Boschen, 1967 (Box 87, Folder 40, Item 6)
  - Legal -- Josiah Macy/PanAm, 1967 (Box 87, Folder 40, Item 7)
  - Birthday wishes -- "Iris", undated (Box 87, Folder 41, Item 1)
  - Birthday wishes -- Jock Francken, undated (Box 87, Folder 41, Item 2)
  - Birthday wishes -- Ilona Neubeck, 1967 (Box 87, Folder 41, Item 3)
  - Birthday wishes -- Josef S. Huber, 1967 (Box 87, Folder 41, Item 4)
  - Birthday wishes -- Josef Wesely, 1967 (Box 87, Folder 41, Item 5)
  - Birthday wishes -- Howard B. Gotlieb, 1967 (Box 87, Folder 41, Item 6)
  - Birthday wishes -- Anita Daniel, undated (Box 87, Folder 41, Item 7)
  - Birthday wishes -- Udo Kortmann, 1963 (Box 87, Folder 42, Item 1)
  - Birthday wishes -- Gerhard Laudehr, 1963 (Box 87, Folder 42, Item 2)
  - Birthday wishes -- Heinz Kirschner, 1963 (Box 87, Folder 42, Item 3)
  - Birthday wishes -- Margaritha Willrodt, 1963 (Box 87, Folder 42, Item 4)
  - Birthday wishes -- Hans Neuhaus, 1963 (Box 87, Folder 42, Item 5)
  - Birthday wishes -- Hermann Banniza, 1963 (Box 87, Folder 42, Item 6)
  - Birthday wishes -- Theodor Moritz, 1963 (Box 87, Folder 42, Item 7)
  - Birthday wishes -- Udo Jacobs, 1963 (Box 87, Folder 42, Item 8)
  - Birthday wishes -- Liz Hiller, 1963 (Box 87, Folder 42, Item 9)
  - Birthday wishes -- A. Tutsch, 1963 (Box 87, Folder 42, Item 10)
  - Birthday wishes -- Lotte Preuß, 1963 (Box 87, Folder 42, Item 11)
  - Birthday wishes -- Wilhelm Damwerth, 1963 (Box 87, Folder 42, Item 12)
  - Birthday wishes -- Wilhelm Lichtenfeld, 1963 (Box 87, Folder 42, Item 13)
  - Birthday wishes -- Kurt Desch, 1963 (Box 87, Folder 42, Item 14)
  - Birthday wishes -- A. Schwaller, 1963 (Box 87, Folder 42, Item 15)
  - Birthday wishes -- Willy Droemer, 1963 (Box 87, Folder 42, Item 16-17)
  - Birthday wishes -- Leopold Weiller, 1963 (Box 87, Folder 42, Item 18)
  - Birthday wishes -- Miklós Weisz, 1963 (Box 87, Folder 42, Item 19)
  - Birthday wishes -- Käthe Wimber, undated (Box 87, Folder 42, Item 20)
  - Birthday wishes -- Inge Bernshausen, 1963 (Box 87, Folder 42, Item 21)
  - Birthday wishes -- Hardi Reller, undated (Box 87, Folder 42, Item 22)
  - Birthday wishes -- Willy Brandt, Fritz Erler, Herbert Wehner, Alfred Nau, 1966 (Box 87, Folder 42, Item 23)
  - Birthday wishes -- Jupp Francken, 1963 (Box 87, Folder 42, Item 24)
  - Birthday wishes -- Hans Helmut Kirst, 1963 (Box 87, Folder 42, Item 25)
  - Birthday wishes -- Georg Diederichs//Niedersächsischer Ministerpräsident, 1963 (Box 87, Folder 42, Item 26)
  - Birthday wishes -- Heinz Liepmann, Ruth Liepmann, 1963 (Box 87, Folder 42, Item 27)
  - Birthday wishes -- Schnabel/Verlag J. Fink, 1963 (Box 87, Folder 42, Item 28)
  - Birthday wishes -- Willy Brandt/Federal Minister for Foreign Affairs, 1968 (Box 87, Folder 43, Item 1)
  - Birthday wishes -- Olga Feist, 1968 (Box 87, Folder 43, Item 2)
  - Birthday wishes -- Guido Pancaldi, undated (Box 87, Folder 43, Item 3)
  - Birthday wishes -- Waldo Riva, 1968 (Box 87, Folder 43, Item 4)
  - Birthday wishes -- "Gipsy," "Günther", circa 1968 (Box 87, Folder 43, Item 5)
  - Birthday wishes -- Harry Meyen, 1968 (Box 87, Folder 43, Item 6)
  - Birthday wishes -- Fritz Kortner, 1968 (Box 87, Folder 43, Item 7)
  - Birthday wishes -- Gerhard Storz/Deutsche Akademie für Sprache und Dichtung, 1968 (Box 87, Folder 43, Item 8)
  - Birthday wishes -- Heinz M. Zellermayer, 1968 (Box 87, Folder 43, Item 9)
  - Birthday wishes -- Jochen Huth, 1968 (Box 87, Folder 43, Item 10)
  - Birthday wishes -- Kurt Raeck, 1968 (Box 87, Folder 43, Item 11)
  - Birthday wishes -- Falk Volkhardt, 1968 (Box 87, Folder 43, Item 12)
  - Birthday wishes -- Hansi Carlo Sulzer, 1968 (Box 87, Folder 43, Item 13)
  - Birthday wishes -- Bruno Heck, 1968 (Box 87, Folder 43, Item 14)
  - Birthday wishes -- Marianne Krell, 1968 (Box 87, Folder 43, Item 15)
  - Birthday wishes -- Gaby Lütjens-Throbecke, 1968 (Box 87, Folder 43, Item 16)
  - Birthday wishes -- Harriet F. Pilpel, 1968 (Box 87, Folder 43, Item 17)
  - Birthday wishes -- Sam Salz, 1968 (Box 87, Folder 43, Item 18)
  - Birthday wishes -- Giacomo Thommen, 1968 (Box 87, Folder 43, Item 19)
  - Birthday wishes -- "Shifra," "Luciano", 1968 (Box 87, Folder 43, Item 20)
  - Birthday wishes -- Elly, 1968 (Box 87, Folder 43, Item 21)
  - Birthday wishes -- Gert, 1968 (Box 87, Folder 43, Item 22)
  - Birthday wishes -- "Hilda," "George", 1968 (Box 87, Folder 43, Item 23)
  - Birthday wishes -- Denver Lindley, 1968 (Box 87, Folder 43, Item 24)
  - Birthday wishes -- Georg Diederichs/Minister-president of Lower Saxony, 1968 (Box 87, Folder 43, Item 25)
  - Birthday wishes -- Louis Ferdinand, 1968 (Box 87, Folder 43, Item 26)
  - Birthday wishes -- Licci Hans, 1968 (Box 87, Folder 43, Item 27)
  - Birthday wishes -- "Ingeborg", 1968 (Box 87, Folder 43, Item 28)
  - Birthday wishes -- Olga Schey, 1968 (Box 87, Folder 43, Item 29)
  - Birthday wishes -- Dominique Aucleres, 1968 (Box 87, Folder 43, Item 30)
  - Birthday wishes -- Walter Goedi, 1968 (Box 87, Folder 43, Item 31)
  - Birthday wishes -- Verlag Kiepenheuer & Witsch, 1968 (Box 87, Folder 43, Item 32)
  - Birthday wishes -- Hermann J. Abs, 1968 (Box 87, Folder 43, Item 33)
  - Birthday wishes -- "Bill," "MARTHA", 1968 (Box 87, Folder 43, Item 34)
  - Birthday wishes -- Louis G. Robinet, 1968 (Box 87, Folder 43, Item 35)
  - Birthday wishes -- Eric Rénné, 1968 (Box 87, Folder 43, Item 36)
  - Birthday wishes -- "Marion," "Nico", 1968 (Box 87, Folder 43, Item 37)
  - Birthday wishes -- Willy Brandt, Helmut Schmidt, Herbert Wehner, Alfred Nau, 1968 (Box 87, Folder 43, Item 38)
  - Birthday wishes -- Vera Kalman, 1968 (Box 87, Folder 43, Item 39)
  - Birthday wishes -- Franz Lappe, 1968 (Box 87, Folder 43, Item 40)
  - Birthday wishes -- Avv. Marcionni, 1968 (Box 87, Folder 43, Item 41)
  - Birthday wishes -- Robert Neumann, 1968 (Box 87, Folder 43, Item 42)
  - Birthday wishes -- José Orabuena, 1968 (Box 87, Folder 43, Item 43)
  - Birthday wishes -- Ginetta Apotheke, 1968 (Box 87, Folder 43, Item 44)
  - Birthday wishes -- Peppi Candolfi, 1968 (Box 87, Folder 43, Item 45)
  - Birthday wishes -- Fritz Rotter, 1968 (Box 87, Folder 43, Item 46)
  - Birthday wishes -- Carlo Weidemeyer, 1968 (Box 87, Folder 43, Item 47)
  - Birthday wishes -- Peter Jacoby, 1968 (Box 87, Folder 43, Item 48)
  - Birthday wishes -- Tildi Ambrosoli, 1968 (Box 87, Folder 43, Item 49)
  - Birthday wishes -- Bolli Palma au Lac, 1968 (Box 87, Folder 43, Item 50)
  - Birthday wishes -- Margret La Roche, 1968 (Box 87, Folder 43, Item 51)
  - Birthday wishes -- Lola Humm, 1968 (Box 87, Folder 43, Item 52)
  - Birthday wishes -- Giovanni Sanfelice, 1968 (Box 87, Folder 43, Item 53)
  - Birthday wishes -- Ivan Fontana, 1968 (Box 87, Folder 43, Item 54)
  - Birthday wishes -- Personale Telegraf o, 1968 (Box 87, Folder 43, Item 55)
  - Birthday wishes -- J. Müller, 1968 (Box 87, Folder 43, Item 56)
  - Birthday wishes -- Heinz Koar, 1968 (Box 87, Folder 43, Item 57)
  - Birthday wishes -- "Babs," "Robert", 1968 (Box 87, Folder 43, Item 58)
  - Birthday wishes -- "Dukas", 1968 (Box 87, Folder 43, Item 59)
  - Birthday wishes -- Julius Baer, 1968 (Box 87, Folder 43, Item 60)
  - Birthday wishes -- Helmut Tuerk, 1968 (Box 87, Folder 43, Item 61)
  - Birthday wishes -- Amelia Rangsit, 1968 (Box 87, Folder 43, Item 62)
  - Birthday wishes -- Frank von Korff, 1968 (Box 87, Folder 43, Item 63)
  - Birthday wishes -- Ingeborg, Dagmar v. Rümker, 1968 (Box 87, Folder 43, Item 64)
  - Birthday wishes -- Weber Baever, 1968 (Box 87, Folder 43, Item 65)
  - Birthday wishes -- Arturo Lotti, 1968 (Box 87, Folder 43, Item 66)
  - Birthday wishes -- Willy Droemer, 1968 (Box 87, Folder 43, Item 67)
  - Birthday wishes -- Gisela Berger, 1968 (Box 87, Folder 43, Item 68)
  - Birthday wishes -- Ellen Wey, 1968 (Box 87, Folder 43, Item 69)
  - Birthday wishes -- Leon le, 1968 (Box 87, Folder 43, Item 70)
  - Birthday wishes -- "Olli", 1968 (Box 87, Folder 43, Item 71)
  - Birthday wishes -- "Ermano", 1968 (Box 87, Folder 43, Item 72)
  - Birthday wishes -- Otto Fein, 1968 (Box 87, Folder 43, Item 73)
  - Birthday wishes -- Vandishoeck, 1968 (Box 87, Folder 43, Item 74)
  - Birthday wishes -- Peter Oesch, 1968 (Box 87, Folder 43, Item 75)
  - Birthday wishes -- Arno Scholz, 1968 (Box 87, Folder 43, Item 76)
  - Birthday wishes -- Douglas Sirk, 1968 (Box 87, Folder 43, Item 77)
  - Birthday wishes -- Andrea Badrutt, 1968 (Box 87, Folder 43, Item 78)
  - Birthday wishes -- Renato Poncini, 1968 (Box 87, Folder 43, Item 79)
  - Birthday wishes -- Norberto Bette, 1968 (Box 87, Folder 43, Item 80)
  - Birthday wishes -- "Speck", 1968 (Box 87, Folder 43, Item 81)
  - Birthday wishes -- Eric Burger, 1968 (Box 87, Folder 43, Item 82)
  - Birthday wishes -- Peter Schifferli, 1968 (Box 87, Folder 43, Item 83)
  - Birthday wishes -- Kanton Tessin, undated (Box 87, Folder 43, Item 84)
  - Birthday wishes -- Botschafter der BRD, 1968 (Box 87, Folder 43, Item 85)
  - Birthday wishes -- Caroline Birman, 1968 (Box 87, Folder 43, Item 86)
  - Birthday wishes -- Heinz Koar, circa 1967 (Box 87, Folder 43, Item 87)
  - Birthday wishes -- Elga Ludwig, 1968 (Box 87, Folder 43, Item 88)
  - Birthday wishes -- Lil Radogna, 1968 (Box 87, Folder 43, Item 89)
  - Birthday wishes -- Peter Flach, 1968 (Box 87, Folder 43, Item 90)
  - Birthday wishes -- Marta Feuchtwanger, 1968 (Box 87, Folder 43, Item 91)
  - Birthday wishes -- Heinrich Lübke, 1968 (Box 87, Folder 43, Item 92)
  - Rosa Kramer, Josef Kramer, 1933-1940 (Box 87, Folder 44, Item 1-2)
  - Rosa Kramer, 1967 (Box 87, Folder 44, Item 3-4)
  - Jutta Zambona, 1929-1967 (Box 87, Folder 45, Item 1-40)
  - Otto M. Heufer, 1968 (Box 87, Folder 45, Item 41)
  - Jutta Zambona, 1968-1969 (Box 87, Folder 45, Item 42-43)
  - Ruth Albu, circa 1929-1940 (Box 87, Folder 46, Item 1-17)
  - Ingrid Bergmann, 1946-1948 (Box 87, Folder 47, Item 1-4)
  - Freiherr von Buchwald, 1932 (Box 87, Folder 48, Item 1-4)
  - Franz Theodor Csokor, 1950-1968 (Box 87, Folder 49, Item 1-3)
    Includes "Ein Heldenleben Eleanora Duse" manuscript
  - Richard Dehmel, circa 1930-1938 (Box 87, Folder 50, Item 1)
  - Marlene Dietrich, 1921-1962 (Box 87, Folder 51, Item 1-17)
  - Otto Dix, 1952 (Box 87, Folder 52, Item 1)
  - Kasimir Edschmid, 1952 (Box 87, Folder 53, Item 1)
  - Annelise Friedmann, 1968-1969 (Box 87, Folder 54, Item 1-3)
  - Hans Habe, 1963 (Box 87, Folder 55, Item 1)
  - Kurt Hiller, 1952 (Box 87, Folder 56, Item 1)
  - Rolf Hochhuth, 1968 (Box 87, Folder 57, Item 1)
  - Karen Horney, 1950 (Box 87, Folder 58, Item 1)
  - Ellen Janssen, 1949-1950 (Box 87, Folder 59, Item 1-16)
  - Ellen Janssen-Donham, 1967-1970 (Box 87, Folder 59, Item 17-18)
  - Vera Kalman, 1968-1970 (Box 87, Folder 60, Item 1-4)
  - Richard Katz, 1954-1968 (Box 87, Folder 61, Item 1-4)
  - Werner Keller, 1968 (Box 87, Folder 62, Item 1)
  - Benedicta M. Kempner, after 1960 (Box 87, Folder 63, Item 1)
  - Robert M. W. Kempner, 1960-1964 (Box 87, Folder 63, Item 2-7)
  - Robert M. W. Kempner, B. M. Kempner, 1967 (Box 87, Folder 63, Item 8)
  - Benedicta M. Kempner, 1967 (Box 87, Folder 63, Item 9)
  - Robert M. W. Kempner, 1967 (Box 87, Folder 63, Item 10)
  - Benedicta M. Kempner, Robert M. W. Kempner, 1968 (Box 87, Folder 63, Item 11)
  - Heinz Koar, 1966 (Box 87, Folder 64, Item 1)
  - Arthur Koestler, undated (Box 87, Folder 65, Item 1)
  - Annette Kolb, 1950 (Box 87, Folder 66, Item 1)
  - Hedy Lamarr, 1950 (Box 87, Folder 67, Item 1)
  - Else Lasker-Schüler, 1935-1938 (Box 87, Folder 68, Item 1-6)
  - Anita Loos, circa 1958 (Box 87, Folder 69, Item 1-2)
  - Emil Ludwig, 1948 (Box 87, Folder 70, Item 1)
  - Elga Ludwig, 1967 (Box 87, Folder 70, Item 2)
  - Alma Mahler-Werfel, undated (Box 87, Folder 71, Item 1)
  - Gypsy Markoff, 1951 (Box 87, Folder 72, Item 1-11)
  - Augusto Pancaldi, 1967 (Box 87, Folder 72, Item 12)
  - Ruth Marton, 1951-1969 (Box 87, Folder 73, Item 1-17)
  - Michael Musmanno, 1955-1960 (Box 87, Folder 74, Item 1-5)
  - Margot von Opel, undated (Box 87, Folder 75, Item 1)
  - Joachim Pierre Pabst, 1965-1969 (Box 87, Folder 76, Item 1-4)
  - Evelyn Petrowa, 1966-1967 (Box 87, Folder 77, Item 1-2)
  - Lotte Preuß, 1932-1967 (Box 87, Folder 78, Item 1-10)
  - Luise Rainer, 1964 (Box 87, Folder 79, Item 1)
  - Herbert Read, 1929-1961 (Box 87, Folder 80, Item 1-4)
  - Felicitas von Reznicek, 1952-1964 (Box 87, Folder 81, Item 1-9)
  - Carroll Righter, 1967-1970 (Box 87, Folder 82, Item 1-3)
  - Curt Riess, 1956-1957 (Box 87, Folder 83, Item 1-3)
  - Edith Roseveare, 1949-1968 (Box 88, Folder 84, Item 1-2)
  - Joseph Roth, undated (Box 88, Folder 85, Item 1)
  - Hans Sahl, undated (Box 88, Folder 86, Item 1)
  - Annemarie Schwarzenbach, 1933-1937 (Box 88, Folder 87, Item 1-7)
  - Ignazio Silone, 1930 (Box 88, Folder 88, Item 1)
  - Robert Siodmak, 1963 (Box 88, Folder 89, Item 1)
  - Ernst Toller, 1933 (Box 88, Folder 90, Item 1)
  - Friedrich Torberg, 1952-1969 (Box 88, Folder 91, Item 1-8)
  - Lupe Velez, 1941 (Box 88, Folder 92, Item 1-13)
  - Carla Vitelleschi, 1936 (Box 88, Folder 93, Item 1-4)
  - Mary Wigman, before 1933 (Box 88, Folder 94, Item 1)
  - Thornton Wilder, undated (Box 88, Folder 95, Item 1)
  - Natasha P. Wilson, 1949-1970 (Box 88, Folder 96, Item 1-57)
  - Victoria Wolff, 1967 (Box 88, Folder 97, Item 1)
  - Liccie Zuckmayer, Carl Zuckmayer, 1932-1969 (Box 88, Folder 98, Item 1-9)
  - "Anita", undated (Box 88, Folder 99, Item 1)
  - Dolores del Rio, undated (Box 88, Folder 100, Item 1)
  - "Elly", undated (Box 88, Folder 101, Item 1)
  - Frances Cain, 1947-1951 (Box 88, Folder 102, Item 1-3)
  - Grete Müller-Hauenfels, 1949-1954 (Box 88, Folder 103, Item 1-11)
  - Helen Wolff, 1964 (Box 88, Folder 104, Item 1)
  - "Kalis", undated (Box 88, Folder 105, Item 1)
  - Maureen O'Sullivan, 1941-1942 (Box 88, Folder 106, Item 1-3)
  - "Kleines Bißchen", 1936-1937 (Box 88, Folder 107, Item 1-8)
  - "Pat", 1930-1939 (Box 88, Folder 108, Item 1-9)
  - "Penny", 1937-1959 (Box 88, Folder 109, Item 1-13)
  - Rene Baehler, 1949-1951 (Box 88, Folder 110, Item 1-2)
  - "Toni", 1951-1952 (Box 88, Folder 111, Item 1-6)
  - "Tilly", 1951-1952 (Box 88, Folder 112, Item 1-3)
  - Salvador Dali, 1944 (Box 88, Folder 113, Item 1)
  - Helen Wolff, undated (Box 88, Folder 114, Item 1)
  - Jochen Wilke, undated (Box 88, Folder 114, Item 2)
  - Helga James, undated (Box 88, Folder 114, Item 3)
  - Paulette Goddard, undated (Box 88, Folder 114, Item 4)
  - Gerard Bauer, undated (Box 88, Folder 114, Item 5)
  - Charlotte Hostettler, undated (Box 88, Folder 114, Item 6)
  - Arthur Rubinstein, undated (Box 88, Folder 114, Item 7)
  - N. H. Alvise Barozzi, undated (Box 88, Folder 114, Item 8)
  - Rudolf Augstein, undated (Box 88, Folder 114, Item 9)
  - "Der kleine Russe", undated (Box 88, Folder 114, Item 10)
  - Lupe Velez, undated (Box 88, Folder 114, Item 11)
  - Edelsheim-Gyulai, undated (Box 88, Folder 114, Item 12)
  - Charlotte Gesau, undated (Box 88, Folder 114, Item 13)
  - Marcel Champion, undated (Box 88, Folder 114, Item 14)
  - Willy Droemer, undated (Box 88, Folder 114, Item 15)
  - Unknown sender, undated (Box 88, Folder 114, Item 16)
  - Elisabeth Bergner, 1941 (Box 88, Folder 114, Item 17)
  - Joachim Pierre Pabst, undated (Box 88, Folder 114, Item 18)
  - Rosa Kramer, undated (Box 88, Folder 114, Item 19)
  - "Frede", undated (Box 88, Folder 114, Item 20)
  - Marlene Dietrich, undated (Box 88, Folder 114, Item 21)
  - G. G., undated (Box 88, Folder 114, Item 22)
  - "Carla Margot", 1949 (Box 88, Folder 114, Item 23)
  - Augusto Pancaldi, 1961 (Box 88, Folder 114, Item 24)
  - Francesca Knittel-Norsa, undated (Box 88, Folder 114, Item 25)
  - Lupe Velez, undated (Box 88, Folder 114, Item 26)
  - Otto Caracciola, undated (Box 88, Folder 114, Item 27)
  - G. G., undated (Box 88, Folder 114, Item 28)
  - "Lisl", undated (Box 88, Folder 114, Item 29)
  - "Ellen", undated (Box 88, Folder 114, Item 30)
  - Jacques Béhar, undated (Box 88, Folder 115, Item 1)
  - Elie R. Béhar, undated (Box 88, Folder 115, Item 2)
  - H. Brown, undated (Box 88, Folder 115, Item 3)
  - Emile-Jean Wolf, undated (Box 88, Folder 115, Item 4)
  - Eveline Petrowa, 1967 (Box 88, Folder 115, Item 5)
  - "Hedi", undated (Box 88, Folder 115, Item 6)
  - E. A. O. Fulde, 1961 (Box 88, Folder 115, Item 7)
  - Aristide Matera, 1966 (Box 88, Folder 115, Item 8)
  - Paul Verhoeven, 1956 (Box 88, Folder 115, Item 9)
  - Robert Wallis, undated (Box 88, Folder 115, Item 10)
  - Sam Gherson, 1938 (Box 88, Folder 115, Item 11)
  - Hans Wagner, undated (Box 88, Folder 115, Item 12)
  - Scala, 1967 (Box 88, Folder 115, Item 13)
- Series 3C: Correspondence with Attached Manuscripts, 1931-1970; 2.5 Linear Feet in 3 manuscript boxes and 2 half manuscript boxes.
  This series contains manuscripts received by Remarque with accompanying correspondence.
  - Dieter Könkler, 1945, 1964 (Box 88, Folder 1, Item 1)
    Includes "End of War" report
  - Kurt Kaufmann, 1967 (Box 88, Folder 1, Item 2)
    Includes advertisements and theses: "Was können wir in den nächsten 10 Jahren erwarten?"
  - Siegfried Streifler, 1953 (Box 88, Folder 1, Item 3)
    Includes Siegfried Streifle: "Politisch-psychologische Arbeiten"
  - Peter Bamm, undated (Box 88, Folder 1, Item 4)
    Includes "Traktat eines Kassenarztes vom Wedding über den Infarkt"
  - Heinrich Boltze, 1931 (Box 88, Folder 1, Item 5)
  - Simon Wiesenthal, 1969 (Box 88, Folder 1, Item 6)
  - Christian Limbourg, 1970 (Box 88, Folder 2, Item 1-2)
    Includes Christian Limbourg: "Eine Ausarbeitung über Erich Maria Remarque"
  - Unknown sender, undated (Box 88, Folder 3)
    Includes "Inherit the Wind" raw translation
  - Heinrich Boltze, undated (Box 88, Folder 4)
    Includes Heinrich Boltze: "Fünf Monate Liebe"
  - J. Stein, 1930 (Box 88, Folder 5, Item 1-1a)
    Includes Albert Alba: "Paul Lothars Jugend"
  - Ruth Marton, Mohrbooks, undated (Box 89, Folder 6)
    Includes Ruth Marton: "The Divorcees"
  - Walter Sorell, undated (Box 89, Folder 7)
    Includes Walter Sorell: "The Flowering of the barren fig tree. A requiem by Walter Sorell"
  - Hart Sprager, undated (Box 89, Folder 8)
    Includes Hart Sprager: "Silver Dollar"
  - Karl von Feilitzsch, 1933 (Box 89, Folder 9)
    Includes Karl von Feilitzsch: "Was ist das Furchtbarste? C'est la neurose! Roman"
  - J. Halle, 1934 (Box 89, Folder 10)
    Includes Georg Frey: "Die Dorfheilige. Eine Begebenheit aus Deutschlands Nachkriegszeit"
  - Unknown sender, undated (Box 89, Folder 11)
    Includes "Zwischen Himmel und Erde. Aus dem Leben eines Schäfers"
  - Lanernia, 1953 (Box 89, Folder 12)
    Includes Lanernia: "Don Valerio"
  - Henri Ellenberger, undated (Box 89, Folder 13)
    Includes Henri Ellenberger: "Multiple Personalities"
  - Robert Lantz, 1958 (Box 89, Folder 14)
    Includes Forrest Davis "The secret history of a surrender"
  - Josef Wolf, 1959 (Box 89, Folder 15)
    Includes Josef Wolf: "On the Beach", artistic advice and directing dialogue
  - Aswell-Snow, 1962 (Box 89, Folder 16)
    Includes Aswell-Snow: "World of Carmel-Snow"
  - Simon Wiesenthal, 1968 (Box 90, Folder 17)
    Includes Simon Wiesenthal: "Die Sonnenblume"
  - Ruth Unzicker, 1963 (Box 90, Folder 18)
    Includes Martin Kristen: "No Discharge" and Robert Wallis: "Zusammenfassung"
  - Unknown sender, undated (Box 110, Folder 19)
    Includes Henri Montherlant: "Das Chaos und die Nacht"
  - Hellmuth Kutzahn, 1961 (Box 110, Folder 20)
    Includes Hellmuth Kurtzahn: „Das Gatter. Ein Zeitstück in 4 Akten"
  - Unknown sender, undated (Box 110, Folder 21)
    Includes John S. White, Dept. Engl., Adelphi University: „Remarque's Im Westen nichts Neues / All Quiet on the Western Front"
  - Unknown sender, 1933 (Box 114, Folder 22)
    Includes Véra Naval: „Der Fall Noskov"
  - Ernst Questor, 1939 (Box 114, Folder 23)
    Includes Ernst Questor: „Warum vergißt man uns! Eine Aufforderung"
- Series 3D: Umfeldkorrespondenz, 1929-1970; 0.5 Linear Feet in 1 manuscript box.
  This series contains miscellaneous correspondence to Remarque, Paulette Goddard, and Jeanne Zambona, as well as others. It includes letters from T.E. Lawrence writing about All Quiet on the Western Front; letters related to translation and publication rights to Remarque's works; contract negotiations; and letters of condolence to Goddard on Remarque's death.
  - "Arthur" in New York to Alix de Rothschild in New York, undated (Box 90, Folder 1, Item 1)
  - T.E. Shaw in Plymouth to Herbert Read, 1929 (Box 90, Folder 1, Item 2)
  - T.E. Shaw in Plymouth to Herbert Read, 1929 (Box 90, Folder 1, Item 3)
  - Ullstein Verlag to Gaupp, 1931 (Box 90, Folder 1, Item 4)
  - Unknown sender to Otto Klement in London, 1937 (Box 90, Folder 1, Item 5)
  - Deutscher Verlag in Berlin to Putnam + Co in London, 1939 (Box 90, Folder 1, Item 6)
  - Eidgenössische Justiz in Bern to Walter Feilchenfeldt in St. Gallen, 1946 (Box 90, Folder 1, Item 7)
  - Walter Garboni in Bern to Rosa Kramer in Porto Ronco, 1946 (Box 90, Folder 1, Item 8)
  - G. Gautschi to Schweizerische Bankgesellschaft in Locarno, 1948 (Box 90, Folder 1, Item 9)
  - O. Schultz in Unteruhldingen to Louise Sarre in Ascona, 1950 (Box 90, Folder 1, Item 10)
  - Vito Marcantino in New York to Marie Valois in New York, 1951 (Box 90, Folder 1, Item 11)
  - Rubinstein, Nash + Co. in London to Harriet Pilpel in New York, 1953 (Box 90, Folder 1, Item 12)
  - Rinklaters + Paines in London to Rubinstein, Nash + Co. in London, 1953 (Box 90, Folder 1, Item 13)
  - Rubinstein, Nash + Co. in London to Harriet Pilpel in New York, 1953 (Box 90, Folder 1, Item 14)
  - Harriet Pilpel in New York to Rubinstein, Nash + Co. in London, 1953 (Box 90, Folder 1, Item 15)
  - Harriet Pilpel to Remarque, 1953 (Box 90, Folder 1, Item 16)
  - Elena Noth in New York to Angel Gimenez Ontiz in Barcelona, 1954 (Box 90, Folder 1, Item 17)
  - Elena Noth in New York to Publicacoes Europa-America in Lisboa, 1954 (Box 90, Folder 1, Item 18)
  - Angel Gimenez Ontiz in Barcelona to Elena Noth in New York, 1955 (Box 90, Folder 1, Item 19)
  - Richard Katz in Locarno to M. Humbel in Stetten, 1954 (Box 90, Folder 1, Item 20)
  - Elena Noth in New York to Kiepenheuer + Witsch in Köln, 1955 (Box 90, Folder 1, Item 21)
  - Elena Noth in New York to Angel Gimenez Ontiz in Barcelona, 1955 (Box 90, Folder 1, Item 22)
  - David Howard in New York to Remarque, undated (Box 90, Folder 1, Item 23)
  - Ernst Freund in London to Doris Hasenfratz in Ascona, 1959 (Box 90, Folder 1, Item 24)
  - Djordje Mandic in Belgrad to Kristall in Hamburg, 1959 (Box 90, Folder 1, Item 25)
  - Sequohan in Paris to Sam Salz in Paris, 1960 (Box 90, Folder 1, Item 26)
  - M. Mantovani in Como to Paulette Remarque in Porto Ronco, 1961 (Box 90, Folder 1, Item 27)
  - C. Kyprianos in Athen to Kiepenheuer & Witsch in Köln, 1961 (Box 90, Folder 1, Item 28)
  - Erno Theis in Osnabrück to Kiepenheuer + Witsch in Köln, 1967 (Box 90, Folder 1, Item 29)
  - Harriet Pilpel in New York to M.D. Deshmukh in Bombay, 1968 (Box 90, Folder 1, Item 30)
  - Stanley F. Glass in New York to Robert Lantz in New York, 1969 (Box 90, Folder 1, Item 31)
  - Paulette Goddard to Rosa Kramer, undated (Box 90, Folder 1, Item 32)
  - Kommandit Gesellschaft in München to Jeanne Zambona in Porto Ronco, 1933 (Box 90, Folder 2, Item 1)
  - Trudel Schmidt in Hannover to Paulette Goddard in Porto Ronco, 1970 (Box 90, Folder 3, Item 1)